#### **Curriculum Vitae**

# **Daniel Joseph Gomez**

5250 Case Dr, Suite 332 Pleasanton, CA 94566 209.407.8614 – danielgomez@ufl.edu

## **Objective**

My career interests are in the applications cellular biology of fending off emerging pathogens, solving diseases with molecular, biophysical, and biotechnical techniques. I will gain the ins and outs of the Omics through academia research. I can present data (talk/poster) as it critical to the research process. My works include MDs, PhDs fellows, and graduate students, this gave me the insight to the work ethic necessary for a career in medicinal chemistry. Technical writing has always pleased me because I was able to tell intricate biological stories. I would like to describe molecular mechanisms, create molecular inventions, and include the macromolecules that have elegant structures and functional catalyst that point to relevant detections (infections, diseases, disorders, etc), biomarkers, and extract the pathological implications. After obtaining my BS degree, I will be applying for doctoral candidacy.

#### **Education**

**Bachelor of Science.** University of Florida. Gainesville, FL Department of Microbiology and Cell Science, UF/IFAS-CALS Microbiology and Cell Science

Anticipated 2018-21

John A. Burns School of Medicine, Johns Hopkins University
Department of Tropical Medicine, Medical Microbiology, and Pharmacology
Relevant Graduate Coursework

2012-2013

- Intro to the Neurosciences
- Translational Research in NeuroAIDS and Mental Health (TR-NAMH)

## **Professional Experience**

Scientific Ambassador. UF. Gainesville, FL

Dec 2018 - Present

- Raise awareness of Agricultural and Life Science
- The Microbiome
- General Virology
- Molecular Biology
- Biochemistry

#### Research and Development Coordinator. dosist. San Francisco, CA

Dec 2015-Feb 2016

- CRO selection and negotiation
- Support chief officers and develop market strategies

**Research Technician.** John A. Burns School of Medicine (JABSOM), Honolulu, HI. Aug 2012-Dec 2013 Department of Tropical Medicine, Medical Microbiology, and Pharmacology

- Developing a drug delivery system for HIV-1 Disease in the BBB.
- FACS, Mouse handling, qPCR, NanoDrop
- Autoclave, Vortex, Centrifuge, cell-culture

**Research Associate.** JABSOM Tropical Medicine, Medical Microbiology, and Pharmacology.

Honolulu, HI

Jan 2012 - June 2013

- Developing an immunohistochemistry (IHC) system for JCPyV and HIV-1 Disease.
- PI- Dr. Shiramizu, Dr. Nerurkar (~32hrs/week).

**Biology Assistant**. JABSOM Department of Tropical Medicine, Medical Microbiology, and Pharmacology. Honolulu, HI

2012-13

- Develop blood-brain barrier for permeability assays
- Flow Cytometry (FACS)
- qPCR

# **Research Experience**

#### Research and Development Coordinator. dosist. San Francisco, CA

Dec 2015-Feb 2016

- Developing disposable bioengineered micro dosed vape pens as deliverables for market.
- Research Human trials (~40hrs/week).
- Dosist pens (relief, bliss, clam, sleep, passion, arousal)

**Research Assistant.** UCSD School of Medicine Division of Neuroanesthesia. La Jolla, CA

Jan 2014-Jun 2014

- Developing a drug delivery system for Neurocardiological Disease protection.
- Caveolin scaffolding life support for heart organ
- PI- Dr. Patel (~5-15hrs/week).

**Research Associate.** JABSOM Tropical Medicine, Medical Microbiology, and Pharmacology.

Honolulu, HI Jan 2014-Jun 2014

- Developing an immunohistochemistry system for JCPyV and HIV-1 Disease.
- Immunocytochemistry procedures in kidney and brain
- PI- Dr. Nerurkar (~40hrs/week).

Research Associate. John A. Burns School of Medicine (JABSOM), Honolulu, HI.

Aug 2012-July 2013

- Developing a drug delivery system for HIV-1 Disease in the BBB.
- PI- Dr. Shiramizu (40hrs/week).

#### **Research Interests**

Chemical Biology	Molecular Biology	Neuro-oncology
Immunology	Translational Research	Neuroscience
Drug metabolism	Computational Biology	<b>Emerging Pathogens</b>

#### Lab skills

Cell culture (Microbial)	DNA synthesis	PCR/qPCR	
Mouse handling	Flow cytometry (in vitro)	R	
Bioinformatics	Microscopy	NGS Sequencing	
Gal Flactrophoracis	Dython	Western blots	

Gel Electrophoresis Western blots Python Drug encapsulation DNA/RNA extraction Toxicity assays

Excellent computer and analytical skills using a large variety of programs and software, excellent public presentation skills

## **Publications**

Anticipated 2020

#### **Awards and Honors**

## **Undergraduate Research Opportunities Program (UROP) Award**

2013

• \$5000 award.

#### 2020 DiVERGE Program. Scripps Research. Jupiter, FL

Jan 2020

- Science identity and the culture of science
- Crafting applications, Research Writing, Constructing a compelling self-introduction
- Internships and Ongoing research
- The history and background of Scripps Research

## **Teaching Experience**

## **Undergraduate Teaching Assistant.** 20hrs/week

2011

- CHEM161 General Chemistry (Dr. Talisman)
- CHEM161L General Chemistry Lab I (Dr. Talisman)

#### **University Tutor.** 15hrs/week

2011

• CHEM161 General Chemistry (Dr. Hemscheidt)

# Tutor. 10hrs/week

2012

Organic Chemistry Tutor

## **Medical and Clinical Experience**

## Volunteer (Shadowing)

2012

• Observed Dr. Slavin, pediatrics and clinical geneticist, in the Medical Genetics section, City of Hope (9 hours/month)

## **Certifications**

IRB Training March 2019

Life Sciences Responsible Conduct of Research Course (RCR)

March 2019

Medical School Pathology – Certificate of Achievement June 2018

DNA Research with Biopython Nov 2017

Data Science and Machine Learning Bootcamp with R Oct 2017

Google's Go (golang) Programming Language Oct 2017

Python for Data Science and Machine Learning Sep 2017

# **Community Service**

Market Research. Berkeley Humane	2014
Animal Welfare	
Community Wellness Advocate. American Cancer Society	2014
Social Services	

# **International Experience**

international Experience	
Teacher. English Language	Summer 2005
• Thailand, Laos	
Violinist. Orchestra	Summer 2006
• France, Belgium	

#### **Technical Skills**

Computer proficiency (MS office, Stats, SAS, R), 7 years of lab and research experience, technical writing, strong organizational and leadership skills, project management, Organizational leadership

# **Professional Organization Membership**

The American Society for Cell Biology (ASCB)	2019
American Society for Microbiology	2020
The Journal of Experimental Biology	2014

Transforming the Future through Science Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology

The Journal of Immunology (AAI)

2013

**AAI Centennial** 

A Century of Excellence: Celebrating 100 Years of The Journal of Immunology The American Association of Immunologists, Inc.

## **Hobbies**

Designing, Drafting, Drawing, Stagecraft, Lighting and Sound, Violin Music, Travelling, Photography, Cooking, Health and Fitness